# RICK KNOWLTON

Full-Stack Developer

## CONTACT

- (717) 419-0684
- mrickknowlton.github.io
- 34 Court Street Dover, NH 03820

#### **EDUCATION**

## **PENNSYLVANIA STATE** UNIVERSITY

2006 - 2011

State College, PA

#### **SKILLS**

Adobe Creative Suite

Bootstrap

CSS/SCSS

**Express** 

Google Firebase

**HTML** 

**JavaScript** jQuery

Material UI

MongoDB

MySQL

Node.js

NPM/Yarn

Phaser

React

Redux

Webpack

# CONNECT

- in linkedin.com/rickknowlton
- www.github.com/rickknowlton

# **ABOUT**

Rick has worked in a variety of positions and places, collecting a unique set of skills and experience along the way. A constant learner and journeyman, Rick likes to solve the hard problems and not just to find a solution, but the best solution possible.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### JUNIOR FULL-STACK WEB DEVELOPER

University of New Hampshire | Durham, NH | May 2018 - December 2018

- Designed and developed 20+ web applications using technologies such as Javascript, ¡Query, MongoDB, Express, React, and Node.js.
- Used AJAX and JSON with Javascript/jQuery for request and response processing of third party API integrations.
- Built a classic platform game using Phaser, Mongo, Express, React, and Node.
- Developed an inventory management application using Node, Express, Passport.js and SQL geared towards small and mid-sized businesses.

#### **GENERAL MANAGER**

Sonny's Tavern | Dover, NH | November 2016 - May 2018

- Managed and operated a full bar and restaurant grossing more than \$1 million in revenue a year and responsible for seeing year-over-year growth of more than 18%.
- Trained and coordinated personnel, instilling a high standard for service and overall guest experience.
- Implemented and designed staff education courses with a focus on expanding and enhancing working knowledge of products and points of service.

## **GENERAL MANAGER**

Spring House Brewing Company | Lancaster, PA | February 2016 - November 2016

- Helped manage a 50,000 square foot facility that included a bar, restaurant, and 10,000 bbl per year brewery.
- Aided in installing more efficient and streamlined business practices that ultimately served to cut costs and expenditures.

#### **BUSINESS CONSULTANT**

Securus Technologies | Philadelphia, PA | July 2014 - February 2016

- · Provided inventory management and payment services to a wide variety of businesses and merchants.
- Acquired more than 100 accounts, generating more than \$2,000,000 in revenue over tenure with company.

#### **OPERATIONS & LOGISTICS MANAGER**

DASHED | Philadelphia, PA | February 2012 - May 2014

- Managed more than 30 couriers and worked with close to 200 partner accounts.
- While working with DASHED volume grew by a margin of 220%, and sales increased by more than 250%.